<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Doge Codes</title>
    <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Doge Codes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://cpp-doge.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 - What Is The CLI</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/guides/command-line-primer/what-is-the-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/guides/command-line-primer/what-is-the-command-line/</guid>
      <description>What Is The Command Line The command line is usually a black screen or window into which you can enter and run plain text commands.
This means you need to know about the commands that are available and how to run them. There are no buttons, no icons and no menus you can use to navigate.
Long ago the command prompt was the only way to use your computer.
Photo Sai Kiran Anagani</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 - About File Paths</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/guides/command-line-primer/about-file-paths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/guides/command-line-primer/about-file-paths/</guid>
      <description>Files &amp;amp; Folders Long ago, we used to store information on bits of dead trees on our desks and in boxes. No more.
Photo by Maksym Kaharlytskyi
You have files on your computer. You probably have things like photos, music, videos, spreadsheets, video game saves and many other possible kinds of files.
Your files are organized in folders, much like a traditional old school filing cabinet. One major difference is that folders on a computer can have many other folders and files inside them where usually a physical filing cabinet does not typically have folders inside of other folders (but it could, who knows!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 - CLI Basics</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/guides/command-line-primer/command-line-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/guides/command-line-primer/command-line-basics/</guid>
      <description>Photo Sai Kiran Anagani
The Command Prompt When you open your terminal, you will be greeted with your shell prompt.
Bash In Bash it looks something like this
elmo@doge:~$ INFO
The little squiggle ~ is special, it is short for your local user directory.
PowerShell In PowerShell it looks something like this
C:\Users\elmo&amp;gt; The prompt usually shows you some information about your computer and where you are, like your username and the path to the current working directory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 - Intermediate CLI</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/guides/command-line-primer/command-line-intermediate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/guides/command-line-primer/command-line-intermediate/</guid>
      <description>Photo Sai Kiran Anagani
Scripting You can write programs using the programming language of your shell, usually called your shell scripting language.
These programs can do almost anything.
Some ideas for things you could do
Backup your vacation photos Backup your game saves Run different Minecraft versions with different mods Launch a video game with a high priority for better performance Compile and run a program you wrote Compile and run a program someone else wrote Manage a Git repository Rename hundreds of files at once Resize, rotate, crop and blur hundreds of images at once Aliases Aliases are a way to make common commands shorter, easier and faster to type and run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 - About Environment Variables</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/guides/command-line-primer/about-environment-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/guides/command-line-primer/about-environment-variables/</guid>
      <description>Photo Sai Kiran Anagani
Environment Variables An environment variable is a way to save some info in a place where your programs can always get to it.
You can set environment variables so that all programs have them or only for one program at a time.
Syntax Environment variables look like regular variables in your shell scripting language.
Bash environment variables begin with $ and the name, so for example $HELLO could be an environment variable in Bash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 - Advanced CLI</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/guides/command-line-primer/command-line-advanced/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/guides/command-line-primer/command-line-advanced/</guid>
      <description>Photo Sai Kiran Anagani
Basic Boolean Tests You can use basic boolean tests. This mostly works based on whether another command succeeds or not.
Bash The Test command is the special character [.
The Test command on Linux lets you check if something is true or not.
The test command contains what should hopefully be mostly familiar expressions and ends with ], like this
[ &amp;#34;hello&amp;#34; == &amp;#34;world&amp;#34; ] This checks to see if hello is the same as world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 - Customize</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/guides/command-line-primer/configuring-your-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/guides/command-line-primer/configuring-your-shell/</guid>
      <description>Photo Sai Kiran Anagani
Configuring Your Shell Most shells let you customize your settings through the use of special startup files. Your startup file is just a shell script that runs each time you open your shell.
The Startup File The Bash startup file lives in $HOME/.bashrc. The rc suffix means run control and is a historical thing from Linux systems.
The PowerShell 7 startup file lives in $env:USERPROFILE\Documents\PowerShell\Microsoft.PowerShell_profile.ps1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Phone Doggo</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/pages/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/pages/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello? Yes? This is Doge. About Me About This Blog This is a blog about mostly C++ programming.
Simple, approachable and easy to understand is the goal here.
Deals frequently &amp;amp; frivolously in hyperbolic incendiary claims Wantonly discards pedantry in favor of punchiness, humor, sarcasm and staying power in the mind Calously ignores details in favor of simplicity and ease of understanding for the layman As my Calculus professor once said:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C Compatibility Headers</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/posts/c-compatibility-headers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/posts/c-compatibility-headers/</guid>
      <description>This Is Bad You may often see C++ code like this
#include &amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt; #include &amp;lt;math.h&amp;gt; int main() { float x = sqrt(3.14); printf(&amp;#34;%f&amp;#34;, x); } These are C compatibility headers. Don&amp;rsquo;t use them in C++.
Do This Instead Put the letter c in front, remove the .h and add the std namespace.
#include &amp;lt;cstdio&amp;gt; #include &amp;lt;cmath&amp;gt; int main() { float x = std::sqrt(3.14); std::printf(&amp;#34;%f&amp;#34;, x); } </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating An MCVE</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/inferno/minimal-reproducible-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/inferno/minimal-reproducible-example/</guid>
      <description>Basics A Minimal Reproducible Example is exactly enough code to demonstrate your problem, but no more and no less.
Sometimes also known as a Minimal Complete and Viable Example or MCVE.
How Do I Make One? See: Howto Use Wandbox Video
Use an online compiler website that can compile and run your code like
Wandbox Godbolt For smaller examples you can also use the discord bot to compile and run your code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dante&#39;s Inferno</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/inferno/objections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/inferno/objections/</guid>
      <description>Frequently Asked Questions We&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to contact you about your car&amp;rsquo;s extended warranty.
Please be sure your seat backs and tray tables are in their fully upright and locked positions as we begin our final descent into Hell.
Your Honor I Object! We regret to inform you that your programming help insurance has been cancelled.
Your supervisor will be with you shortly.
Why Am I Here People have been wondering this for thousands of years and we still don&amp;rsquo;t have many good answers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>G&#43;&#43; And Clang&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/posts/gcc-clang-plus-plus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/posts/gcc-clang-plus-plus/</guid>
      <description>What Is This About? A common mistake is not running the right command when compiling a C++ program.
So Which Command Do I Use? If you are using GCC then use the g++ command
g++ main.cpp -o main If you are using Clang then use the clang++ command
clang++ main.cpp -o main Why Is This A Thing? The GNU Compiler Collection is known as GCC. Confusingly this collection of compilers also includes a program named gcc, however this is not what you want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getline And Cin</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/posts/getline-cin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/posts/getline-cin/</guid>
      <description>Does Noob A Bamboozle Using getline() together with cin &amp;gt;&amp;gt; is a sharp corner.
This guide will help you figure that out.
The Problem When you use &amp;gt;&amp;gt; to get input from a stream, then the stream does not consume whitespace after your input.
This means for example that if you cin &amp;gt;&amp;gt; up to the end of the line, then the subsequent newline \n character will still remain in the stream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Binary Works</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/posts/how-binary-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/posts/how-binary-works/</guid>
      <description>Binary Numbers How do they work!?
What Is A Number System What Is A Base The base of your number system is how many digits you have.
We doggos use a beef hotdog number system.
No, wait&amp;hellip; we use a base ten number system.
What does that actually mean though?
I&amp;rsquo;m The Only Tigger We have been using base ten for so long in our normal lives, like at the grocery store or when talking about footbal scores, that it just feels natural and normal to most people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links To Stuff</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/pages/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/pages/links/</guid>
      <description>Learn With Games (this is not the only section on this page, keep scrolling for other stuff)
I love games. I love programming.
These are games that teach programming, are turing complete enough to build a full computer inside the game, are about programming or they contain programming inside the game in some way, etc etc.
Shenzhen I/O
Stationeers
Stationeers MIPS Documentation Stationeers MIPS Simulator Space Engineers
12 Free Beginner Coding Games</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should I Use VSCode And MinGW</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/inferno/vscode-mingw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/inferno/vscode-mingw/</guid>
      <description>In 30 Seconds Use Visual Studio. It&amp;rsquo;s FREE! It does everything you want.
Download: Visual Studio
Visual Studio is not VSCode. Don&amp;rsquo;t use VSCode. Don&amp;rsquo;t use MinGW.
What&amp;rsquo;s The Point The point is that an IDE comes with all the tools you need to quickly and easily begin working with C++.
You should probably use an IDE regardless of what kind of computer you have.
I Am Not Using Windows You should probably still use an IDE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wandbox Example Video</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/posts/using-wandbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/posts/using-wandbox/</guid>
      <description>How To Use Wandbox Go To: The Wandbox Online Compiler Website
Here&amp;rsquo;s a video showing how to create a Wandbox example with multiple .cpp files and user input.
NOVIDEO </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is A Data Type</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/posts/what-is-a-data-type/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/posts/what-is-a-data-type/</guid>
      <description>Before You Begin See: How Binary Works
Computer Memory Computers store information in memory as binary numbers.
Transistors Transistors are good at turning on and off. This can easily be used represent a one or a zero.
The information in your computer is managed by a bunch of transitors. You can think of it like being one bit per transistor, meaning each transistor can represent either a zero or a one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which C&#43;&#43; Book?</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/posts/which-cpp-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/posts/which-cpp-book/</guid>
      <description>What Should I Choose? These are pretty good, though I haven&amp;rsquo;t read them all, some may be better or worse. Some may be better for your skill level than others.
You agree to not hold me liable if any of these books eats your first born child, kicks your puppy or is otherwise nasty to you.
I&amp;rsquo;m Literally Broke LearnCPP CppLang Tutorial I Want Something Easy And Fun For Children MIT Scratch FREE Roblox Studio I&amp;rsquo;m Scared Of C++ Code Academy - Learn Python FREE I Am A Beginner Programming: Principles and Practice Using C++ I Have Programming Experience A Tour of C++ Murach&amp;rsquo;s C++ Programming Professional C++ I Want To Know More Scott Meyers C++ Concurrency In Action High Performance C++ I Am Extremely Motivated And I Like Pain The C++ Programming Language I Actually Just Want To Play Video Games Ok, sure, try one of these.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why C&#43;&#43; Instead of C</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/inferno/why-cpp-instead-of-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/inferno/why-cpp-instead-of-c/</guid>
      <description>What Is The Difference? The difference between C++ and C is very large.
Most C++ code is not valid C code.
Most idiomatic C code is very poor C++ code.
Why Should I Use C++? C++ has many features in both the language and its standard library including, in no particular order
Metaprogramming Variadic Templates Lambdas Concurrency and Parellelism Atomics Structured Bindings Regular Expressions Strings, Arrays &amp;amp; Dictionaries Unicode Support Date &amp;amp; Time Functions File And Directory Management Random Number Generation Function Overloads Operator Overloads Classes Inheritance Polymorphism Iterators Ranges Concepts Views &amp;amp; Spans Exceptions Variant Plus there exist many other common useful libraries for things like</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
