<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Limbo on Doge Codes</title>
    <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/limbo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Limbo on Doge Codes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://cpp-doge.github.io/limbo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Attention To Detail</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/limbo/style/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/limbo/style/</guid>
      <description>Why It Matters If it makes my eyes bleed, am I going to be motivated to help?
Attention To Detail Is Important Programming is a detail oriented art. If you neglect details you will make lots of mistakes, your code will be bad, your programs will have errors, you will cause yourself (and others) much undue pain debugging problems you could have easily avoided.
Caring is important If you don&amp;rsquo;t care about something then you won&amp;rsquo;t do a good job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating An MCVE</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/limbo/minimal-reproducible-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/limbo/minimal-reproducible-example/</guid>
      <description>Basics TLDR Shorten your code and post it to Wandbox.org
See also: Howto Use Wandbox Video
What Is It? A Minimal Reproducible Example is exactly enough code to demonstrate your problem, but no more and no less.
Sometimes also known as a Minimal Complete and Viable Example or MCVE.
How Do I Make One? See: Howto Use Wandbox Video
Use an online compiler website that can compile and run your code like</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use An IDE</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/limbo/use-an-ide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/limbo/use-an-ide/</guid>
      <description>In 60 Seconds Use Visual Studio for Windows. It&amp;rsquo;s FREE! It does everything you want.
Download: Visual Studio
Visual Studio is not VSCode, they are different products. Visual Studio comes with a compiler, no need for MinGW. See also I Am Not Using Windows
See also I Want To Use Something Else
Visual Studio doesn&amp;rsquo;t configure itself, you still have to do that, but doing so should be much easier for beginners as compared to VSCode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where Do I Start</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/limbo/where-do-i-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/limbo/where-do-i-start/</guid>
      <description>Where Do I Start Begin by reading your textbook.
But I Don&amp;rsquo;t Have A Textbook Use the one from your syllabus.
But I Don&amp;rsquo;t Have A Syllabus You probably do. Ask your TAs or your professor for book recommendations.
Anyway, you could try a free one like this
Free CompSci Curriculum But I Don&amp;rsquo;t Have A Syllabus Textbook Then get yourself a book, there are free books available.
Paid books are still generally better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why C&#43;&#43; Instead of C</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/limbo/why-cpp-instead-of-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/limbo/why-cpp-instead-of-c/</guid>
      <description>What Is The Difference? The difference from C to C++ is very great.
Most C++ code is not valid C code.
Most idiomatic C code is very poor C++ code.
Why Should I Use C++? C++ has many features in both the language and its standard library including, in no particular order
Metaprogramming Variadic Templates Lambdas Concurrency and Parellelism Atomics Structured Bindings Regular Expressions Strings, Arrays &amp;amp; Dictionaries Unicode Support Date &amp;amp; Time Functions File And Directory Management Random Number Generation Function Overloads Operator Overloads Classes Inheritance Polymorphism Iterators Ranges Concepts Views &amp;amp; Spans Exceptions Variant Plus there exist many other common useful libraries for things like</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
