<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Inferno on Doge Codes</title>
    <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/inferno/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Inferno on Doge Codes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://cpp-doge.github.io/inferno/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Objections</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/inferno/objections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/inferno/objections/</guid>
      <description>Frequently Asked Questions We&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to contact you about your car&amp;rsquo;s extended warranty.
Please be sure your seat backs and tray tables are in their fully upright and locked positions as we begin our final descent into Hell.
Your Honor I Object! We regret to inform you that your programming help insurance has been cancelled.
Your supervisor will be with you shortly.
Why Am I Here People have been wondering this for thousands of years and we still don&amp;rsquo;t have many good answers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Are A Toxic Idiot</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/inferno/you-are-a-toxic-idiot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/inferno/you-are-a-toxic-idiot/</guid>
      <description>Of Course You Are Literally the most important person in the world. All knowing, all seeing, wise beyond your years, intellect beyond comprehension. Everyone should listen to you speak, no one should ever doubt your sage advice.
Why Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t You Be? A prime specimen, a beacon of humility, a bastion of kindness, a champion of morality, a pillar of the community, a solution to all suffering, the center of wisdom and reason, a holy pure light shining from heaven, a righteous fire, savior of puppies and kittens, infallible, a veritable vanguard of humanity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Are Wrong</title>
      <link>https://cpp-doge.github.io/inferno/you-are-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpp-doge.github.io/inferno/you-are-wrong/</guid>
      <description>Why You Are Wrong If You Came Here To Tell Me I Should Say This Other Thing Instead This is a blog mostly aimed at newbies. This blog is probably not for you.
This blog is what it is intended to be for its target audience.
If You Came Here To Tell Me I Should Advise Some Other Probably Advanced Tool Or Technique Instead Reducing Complexity Read about the mission statement and objectives of this blog.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
